<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tristan Knight's Blog</title><link>https://tristanknight.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://tristanknight.github.io/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2020 &lt;a href="mailto:tk1824@nyu.edu"&gt;Tristan Knight&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 14:15:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Diagnosing an Error when Importing tkinter</title><link>https://tristanknight.github.io/posts/resolving-issue-with-tkinter/</link><dc:creator>Tristan Knight</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A couple days ago I encountered a problem while working on a project using 
&lt;a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/tkinter.html"&gt;tkinter&lt;/a&gt;,
a popular Python GUI package. At first glance, everything seemed
fine -- PyCharm appeared to recognize tkinter and nothing suggested anything was amiss. However, when
I tried running my program I got an error message that looked like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://tristanknight.github.io/images/initialerror.png" width="800"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first checked to make sure that I was using the appropriate syntax was importing
the correct tkinter. Perhaps the T needed to be capitalized? No, that's only when using Python 2. After
a couple minutes of Googling, I became confident that the problem was something else. 
Fortunately, the error message offered a helpful suggestion -- perhaps the Python 
I was using hadn't been correctly configured to work with Tk. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After doing a bit more Google searching, it seemed that other people had experienced similar issues.
One commenter &lt;a href="https://github.com/pyenv/pyenv/issues/94#issuecomment-437180736"&gt;suggested&lt;/a&gt; that Mac OSX users install tcl-tk before installing Python with
pyenv. I ran &lt;code&gt;pyenv uninstall 3.8.0&lt;/code&gt; to uninstall Python, installed tcl-tk using &lt;a href="https://brew.sh/"&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt;, and then reinstalled 
Python 3.8.0 using pyenv. 
I confirmed I was using the appropriate version of Python, then tried importing tkinter again, and got the same error message as before.
I ran &lt;code&gt;brew list&lt;/code&gt; and confirmed that Homebrew had in fact installed tcl-tk. I then ran &lt;code&gt;brew info tcl-tk&lt;/code&gt; and got this
helpful message:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://tristanknight.github.io/images/brewinfo.png" width="800"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The message indicated that I needed to add tcl-tk to my PATH. 
I ran the suggested commands, and confirmed that the directives were added to my bash profile.
I tried importing tkinter again, and once again got the same message.
I asked a friend for advice, and she suggested that I uninstall Python again, and then 
run 
&lt;code&gt;env PYTHON_CONFIGURE_OPTS_ARRAY="--with-tcltk-libs='-L/usr/local/opt/tcl-tk/lib -ltcl8.6 -ltk8.6'"&lt;/code&gt;
in my console before reinstalling Python. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did this, and this time when I ran &lt;code&gt;import tkinter&lt;/code&gt; I 
didn't get an error message. Excited, I ran &lt;code&gt;tkinter._test()&lt;/code&gt; and felt a sense of relief as a window 
popped up. My relief didn't last long, however, as I quickly noticed an error message in my console:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://tristanknight.github.io/images/finalerror.png" width="800"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I realized that the window that had appeared failed to display the correct information. Fortunately, 
the problem seemed clear from the error message: the tk.h version didn't match the libtk.a version. After doing a bit of 
Google searching for similar problems, I found that someone had 
&lt;a href="https://github.com/pyenv/pyenv/issues/1375#issuecomment-524280004"&gt;listed a series of steps&lt;/a&gt; to get the latest version of 
tcl-tk to work with the pyenv Python install. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I edited my python-build file, replacing &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$CONFIGURE_OPTS ${!PACKAGE_CONFIGURE_OPTS} 
"${!PACKAGE_CONFIGURE_OPTS_ARRAY}" || return 1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;with &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$CONFIGURE_OPTS --with-tcltk-includes='-I/usr/local/opt/tcl-tk/include' --with-tcltk-libs='-L/usr/local/opt/tcl-tk/lib 
-ltcl8.6 -ltk8.6' ${!PACKAGE_CONFIGURE_OPTS} "${!PACKAGE_CONFIGURE_OPTS_ARRAY}" || return 1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then re-installed Python, and then ran &lt;code&gt;echo -e 'if command -v pyenv 1&amp;gt;/dev/null 2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1; then\n eval "$(pyenv init -)"\nfi' &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.bash_profile&lt;/code&gt;
to update my bash file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I re-started my command line, checked that I was using the right version of Python, successfully
ran &lt;code&gt;import tkinter&lt;/code&gt;, then ran &lt;code&gt;tkinter_test()&lt;/code&gt;. 
This time, the correct window appeared, and there was no error message in the terminal -- I had finally fixed the problem!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When using so many different tools and technologies that interact in various ways, it's inevitable that 
sometimes things don't work as they should. Fortunately, there are only so many things that can go wrong, and oftentimes 
someone else has experienced the same problem and devised a solution. Even though this ended up being the case here, 
it still took me a few hours to resolve the tkinter issue. But while troubleshooting the problem was frustrating,
I ended up feeling  quite a bit of satisfaction after the test finally passed successfully. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://tristanknight.github.io/posts/resolving-issue-with-tkinter/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 10:38:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Test-Driven Development</title><link>https://tristanknight.github.io/posts/test-driven-development/</link><dc:creator>Tristan Knight</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, I've been working through &lt;a href="https://www.obeythetestinggoat.com/"&gt;Obey the Testing Goat!&lt;/a&gt;, 
a book that covers test-driven development for web-development with Django. 
Test-driven development (TDD) is a development practice in which developers first write tests and then 
write the code that is to be tested. This is in contrast to other practices in which code is tested after being written. 
Though I have encountered testing in the past, test-driven development's emphasis 
on writing tests first and is quite different from the programming styles I have used before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Types of testing&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In software development, two common types of tests are &lt;strong&gt;unit tests&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;functional tests&lt;/strong&gt;. 
Functional tests are used to test whether a feature works correctly from the &lt;em&gt;user's&lt;/em&gt; perspective, 
for example, you may want to write a test to check whether a website displays the correct information, or if a button on a site
works as a it should. Functional tests are concerned with whether the feature being tested
works as it should, instead of whether or not the pieces of underlying code work correctly. Functional tests are often accompanied by a user-centered story that 
makes them readable even to people without a programming background. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unit tests, on the other hand, are used to ensure that the &lt;em&gt;code&lt;/em&gt; works as it should. 
Python has a built-in unittest module that includes helpful tools for writing tests. Django 
also has a django.test.TestCase module which contains some Django-specific features. In TDD,
every line of code should be unit-tested, and unit tests should be written before the code itself, which helps ensure that the developer
understands the purpose of the code before writing it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;The TDD process&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Obey the Testing Goat&lt;/em&gt; also discusses the &lt;em&gt;TDD process&lt;/em&gt;, or TDD cycle, which can be summarized as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a (functional or unit) test &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run the test. If it passes, proceed to step 5, otherwise proceed to step 3.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify the reason for the test's failure and write the minimum amount of code needed to fix the error (even if 
the code isn't very well-written)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run the test again, and if it passes proceed to step 5. Otherwise, go back to step 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify code that needs refactoring, and then refactor as necessary. After refactoring,
return to step 2 to ensure that the refactoring didn't inadvertently break the code. If the code does not need refactoring, continue
building the program by returning to step 1 and writing a test for another
piece of &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've found learning about test-driven development to be fascinating, and I can certainly see the utility of writing comprehensive tests
before writing code. However, I feel that the book does a better job of offering a high-level explanation of testing than it does of teaching you &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to write your own tests. 
Although there are plenty examples of tests given, it can be a little difficult translating these examples to actually writing your own tests for completely different programs. 
Therefore, I plan to practice writing unit tests and functional tests while working on person projects going forward in order 
to develop a better understanding of testing.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://tristanknight.github.io/posts/test-driven-development/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 11:52:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>What I learned from using Git as a version control system</title><link>https://tristanknight.github.io/posts/first-post/</link><dc:creator>Tristan Knight</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've recently been learning how to use Git, and I can now see why it is such a popular version
control system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;What is Git and why is version control essential for programmers?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When working on a large project,
some type of version control system is essential -- one needs to be able to keep track of a project's changes and revert to 
a previous version if something goes wrong. Git also assists teams in coordinating work on a project, since it
gives each programmer access to a repository containing the full history of the project's codebase. In addition to simple version control, 
Git provides a multitude of features that improve developers' organization
and productivity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;How does Git work?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After installing and configuring Git, you can easily create a new repository by running the "git init" shell
command in your project's directory. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Git repository has three key areas:
   * The Working Directory, which contains the files you can view and edit on your computer &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Staging Index, which contains files from the working directory which have been added to the staging 
    index by the user but have not yet been committed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Repository, where commits are stored&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;What are some of Git's key features?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a thorough explanation of Git's features, see the &lt;a href="https://git-scm.com/doc"&gt;official 
Git documentation&lt;/a&gt;. However, I have included a sample of Git's key features, 
which give you the ability to do the following: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add changes to the staging index, and commit stages from the staging 
index to the repository with the "git add" and "git commit" commands.
 You can also remove or edit previous commits. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quickly check the commit history with the "git log" command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select which files you'd like Git to ignore &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add a tag (such as a version number) to a particular commit with the "git tag" command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maintain parallel sets of changes with Git's branching functionality. Git's branching feature is key 
in allowing large teams of developers to work on multiple features of a project simultaneously. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to merge independent branches together. Git will also let the user know if there is a merge conflict 
(i.e. if the branches contain conflicting lines of code), which the will then need to resolve manually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://tristanknight.github.io/posts/first-post/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 09:45:52 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>